Class of 1901 Records, 1897-1982
Smith College Archives
Class of 1901 Records
1897-1982
Smith College. Class of 1901.
RG 80 UUID:6e0ea148-68fa-4b73-abf2-10ff07cbf8c1
28 boxes (15.6 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection is in 28 boxes and contains photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, and other memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1901.
The Class of 1901 was the twenty-third entering and graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1901 records, 1897-1982, contain materials describing the history and activities of the Class of 1901, including materials from commencement, reunions, senior dramatics, and other important events. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, songs, newspaper clippings, letters, financial information, and other memorabilia.
Individual biographical files are also available, and often include photographs, photo albums, newspaper clippings, letters and correspondences, and class notes.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1901 records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- General undated (Box 1592, Folder 1)
- Baccalaureate Service 1901 (Box 1592, Folder 2)
- Commencement 1901 (Box 1592, Folder 3)
- Commencement- Photographs 1901 (Box 1592, Folder 4)
- Commencement- Music 1901 (Box 1592, Folder 5)
- Financial (gifts, bequests, etc.) 1962-1975 (Box 1592, Folder 6)
- Freshman Grind by 1900 1897 (Box 1592, Folder 7)
- Freshman Handbook 1897-1898 (Box 1592, Folder 8)
- Groups 1897-1901 (Box 1592, Folder 9)
- Ivy Day 1901 (Box 1592, Folder 10)
- Ivy Day- Photographs 1901 (Box 1592, Folder 11)
- Junior Frolic 1900 (Box 1592, Folder 12)
- Junior Prom 1900 (Box 1592, Folder 13)
- Junior Prom Picnic 1900 (Box 1592, Folder 14)
- Junior-Senior Party for Class of 1900 1900 (Box 1592, Folder 15)
- Ledger 1916-1971 (Box 1593, Folder 1)
- Letters 1951-1971 (Box 1593, Folder 2)
- May Lewis- Ellen Emerson Memorial Fund- correspondence 1960-1976 (Box 1593, Folder 3)
- May Lewis- Ellen Emerson Memorial Fund- history, financial 1921-1970 (Box 1593, Folder 4)
- Minutes 1897-1976 (Box 1593, Folder 5)
- Newsletter 1916-1971 (Box 1593, Folder 6)
- Officers 1955-1977 (Box 1593, Folder 7)
- Reunion Notices from Alumnae Quarterly 1913-1967 (Box 1593.1, Folder 1)
- Reunions 1902 (Box 1593.1, Folder 2)
- Reunions 1906 (Box 1593.1, Folder 3)
- Reunions 1911 (Box 1593.1, Folder 4)
- Reunions 1913 (Box 1593.1, Folder 5)
- Reunions 1916 (Box 1593.1, Folder 6)
- Reunions 1921 (Box 1593.1, Folder 7)
- Reunions 1926 (Box 1593.1, Folder 8)
- Reunions 1931-1936 (Box 1593.1, Folder 9)
- Reunions 1941 (Box 1593.1, Folder 10)
- Reunions 1946 (Box 1593.1, Folder 11)
- Reunions 1950-1951 (Box 1593.1, Folder 12)
- Reunions 1956 (Box 1593.1, Folder 13)
- Reunions Letters 1961 (Box 1593.1, Folder 14)
- Reunions 1961 (Box 1593.1, Folder 15)
- Reunions 1962 (Box 1593.1, Folder 16)
- Reunions 1966 (Box 1593.1, Folder 17)
- Reunions 1971 (Box 1593.1, Folder 18)
- Round Robin 1982 (Box 1593.1, Folder 19)
- Class Secretary 1946-1970 (Box 1594, Folder 1)
- Class Secretary's Notebook 1901-1971 (Box 1594, Folder 2)
- Senior Dramatics 1901 (Box 1594, Folder 3)
- Senior Dramatics 1901 (Box 1594, Folder 4)
- Senior Party at Morris House 1901 (Box 1594, Folder 5)
- Sophomore Reception 1897 (Box 1594, Folder 6)
- Songs undated (Box 1594, Folder 7)
- Class Suppers 1901 (Box 1594, Folder 8)
- Class Supper 1902 (Box 1594, Folder 9)
- Class of 1901- Alumnae Quarterly Notices
  - Ainslie-Burns 1912-1970 (Box 1595, Folder 1)
  - Caldwell-Durkee 1912-1973 (Box 1595, Folder 2)
  - Fales-Grumbine 1912-1970 (Box 1595, Folder 3)
  - Hanna-Lord 1909-1970 (Box 1595, Folder 4)
  - Mason-Putman 1910-1971 (Box 1595, Folder 5)
  - Reeves-Sutton 1910-1970 (Box 1595, Folder 6)
  - Taylor-Zink 1910-1971 (Box 1595, Folder 7)